(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-15T08:35:37.387773",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
我が輩は1日後に最強のLIVEをする予定のVTuber！
I'm a VTuber scheduled to hold the ultimate LIVE in one day!
おい！信じられないけど明日がLIVE当日らしいよ！？
Hey! Believe it or not, tomorrow is apparently the LIVE day?!
ここで我が輩のLIVEにまつわるやらかしエピソードを1つ紹介します。
Here, I'll introduce one blunder episode related to my LIVE.
LIVEのために毎回ちゃんとハッシュタグを決めて、配信画面に出せるように運営さんに予め報告するんだけど…
For every LIVE, I properly decide on a hashtag beforehand and report it to management so it can be shown on stream...
報告した後、LIVE当日のツイートとか我が輩毎回ちょっと間違えてタグツイートしちゃって…
But after reporting, every time on the LIVE day, my tweets... I somehow end up tweeting with the wrong hashtag...
なんと我が輩の公式ハッシュタグ、X(旧Twitter)のトレンドに乗ったことないんだよね〜！
In fact, my official hashtag has never trended on X (formerly Twitter)!
運営さんいつもごめんね！
Management, I'm always sorry!
今回は間違えないよ★
This time I won't make a mistake★
と言うことでみんな！LIVEの応援や当日のツイートは絶対に#ラプラス2周年LIVEでツイートしてね！！
So everyone! For LIVE support and tweets on the day, be sure to tweet with #Laplus2ndAnniversaryLIVE!!
今年こそ！トレンド入りよろしくお願いします！！
This year for sure! Please help us trend!!
どうしたヤブからボーニー？
What's wrong, La+-boni out of nowhere?
気にしないでください。いつもの発作です。
Don't worry about it. It's just her usual spasm.
だって我が輩、悪の秘密結社の総帥だよ！なのになんでアイドルなんかやらなきゃいけないの！
Because I'm the supreme leader of a secret evil society! Why do I have to do idol stuff?!
真逆じゃん！真逆のイメージじゃんかよ！
That's the complete opposite! It's the total opposite image!
こよりとか…うーん、いろはとか？
Koyori or... Hmm, Iroha or?
どーすたでござるか？
What about Dosta?
といいとかかわいいよ。おい！
Poi and others are cute. Hey!
さかまとはどうした？
What about Sakamata?
我が輩も疲れたのー！
I'm tired too!
そもそもアイドルやってくださいって言われたの！
First of all, who was told "please do idol activities"?!
言われてないんかーい！
You weren't told?!
言われてなかった。ってことは我が輩、勝手にアイドルやってた人ってこと！？
I wasn't. That means I was doing idol activities all on my own?!
いやでもバズってたよね、あれ！
Yeah, but it went viral, didn't it, that one!
だいしきゅーだいしゅき
Dai-shikyuu dai-shuki
バズるってことは、たくさんの人に知ってもらえることになるとし、それすなわち！
Trending means getting known by a lot of people, and that means—
世界征服では？それぞれ。
World domination? Each of us.
確かに。確かに。
True. True.
でもさ、フレア先輩のオーラ見てよ！
But hey, look at Flare-senpai's aura!
すっごいキラキラだね！これぞアイドルって感じですね！
It's super sparkly! This is what an idol feels like!
可愛い でござれ！
So cute!
いや…てか、あの、なんか…
Well... I mean, um, like...
ここにいる人はみんなキラキラしてるんだけどさ…
Everyone here is super sparkly, but...
ラプラスのオーラって、なんか…
Laplus's aura is kind of...
禍々しい！
Ominous!
言われなくても分かってるんだよ！
I know even if you don't say it!
我が輩だって！せっかくそろそろ2周年ライブがあるのに！
Even I! When the 2nd anniversary live is coming up soon!
いー、いー、いーーー！！！
Wahh, wahh, waahhh!!!
しょうがないな。
It can't be helped.
やっとりました！
We did it!
仕方ないな。みんなもいいよね？
It can't be helped. Everyone's fine with it too, right?
ラプラス・ダークネスアイドル昇華大作戦！！！！
La+ Darknesss's Idol Elevation Great Operation!!!!
Signalize!
Hi, signalize!
答えをもっと高い空の彼方
The answer is way up high in the sky,
いいえ違うよ
No, that's not right!
僕の目にも見えた地の果て
Even my eyes could see the edge of the earth.
Do that signalize!
激しくなった胸の熱いパワー
The blazing power in my chest has grown so fierce.
そうさみなぎる何かが
Yes, something is welling up,
だから今を信じて
so believe in the present!
始めよう
Let's begin,
ただの憧れじゃないじゃん
it's not just mere yearning.
Chance for me!
残酷な夢が夢で夢になるんだ
A cruel dream turns into a dream of dreams,
ほら挑戦待ってるよ
Look, challenges are waiting!
君と向かう場所はどこだろう
Where is the place we will face?
眩しい希望の中へ
Into the dazzling hope.
望む場所はどこだろう 探しに行こうよ出発だ
Where should we head? Let's go search for it, set off!
向かう場所は未来の
Where we are heading is in the future,
僕らの希望の中に
right within our hopes.
望む場所は未来の輝きが合図 let's go, go!
The place we desire is in the future's gleam—let's go, go!
Hi, visualise!
例えば今日は青い迷路だった
For example, today was a blue maze.
早く抜け出せ
Hurry and break out!
僕と来ればいいさこのまま
It'll be fine if you come with me just as you are.
Do that visualise!
光のように走る不意のエネルギー
Running like light, an untamed energy,
震えるほどの奇跡を
miracles that make you tremble,
だから今は信じて
so believe in the present!
叶えたい
I want to make it come true,
強く願い続けるんだ
keeping on wishing strongly.
Get a luck!
純粋を歌おう 歌え 歌いたいんだ
Let's sing a pure song—I just want to sing, sing!
もう絶望なんかないから
There's no such thing as despair anymore.
やがて生まれ変わる世界を 感じる予感の中で
In a premonition of a world soon to be reborn,
移り変わる世界を求める旅だね前進だ
it's a journey seeking a changing world.
生まれ変わるメロディ
A melody that's reborn,
僕らは希望の中さ
we are right inside our hope.
やっと変わるメロディ 閃いた地図で it's new world!
A newly transforming melody with an inspired map—it's new world!
Do the live, take a chance! do you know, do you know?
Do the love, take a chance! do you know, do you know?
I believe love!!
向かう場所はどこだろう
Where is the place we will face?
眩しい希望の中へ
Into the dazzling hope.
望む場所はどこだろう 探しに行こうよ出発だ
Where should we head? Let's go search for it, set off!
向かう場所は未来の
Where we are heading is in the future,
僕らの希望の中に
right within our hopes.
望む場所は未来の輝きが合図 let's go, go!
The place we desire is in the future's gleam—let's go, go!
Do the live, take a chance! do you know, do you know?
Do the love, take a chance! do you know, do you know?
I believe... love comes!!
Hi, signalize!
Do you know, do you know?
Do the live, take a chance!
Do you know, do you know? Do the light, take a chance!
Do you know, do you know? ああメロディ...
Do you know, do you know? Ah, melody...
向かう場所はどこだろう
Where is the place we will face?
眩しい希望の中へ
Into the dazzling hope.
望む場所はどこだろう 探しに行こうよ出発だ
Where should we head? Let's go search for it, set off!
向かう場所は未来の
Where we are heading is in the future,
僕らの希望の中に
right within our hopes.
望む場所は未来の輝きが合図 let's go, go!
The place we desire is in the future's gleam—let's go, go!
Do the light, take a chance! do you know, do you know?
Do the light, take a chance! do you know, do you know? ああメロディ...
Do the light, take a chance! Do you know, do you know? Ah, melody...
夢みたいに綺麗で泣けちゃうな
This is beautiful like a dream, and makes me want to cry
明るい空
In this bright sky,
見つけた一筋の流れ星
I found a single shooting star.
黄昏に染まる世界が好き
I like it as the world is dyed by the twilight,
素敵なデキゴトを集めるのが好き
and I like gathering lots of wonderful events.
誰にでも一つの物語
Anyone can start their very own story,
自分らしく歩くの いつでもはじめられるよ
and you can start walking at your own pace anytime.
ほら
Look,
溢れる夕映えは優しい光のプレゼント
this overflowing sunset is a present from that gentle light.
夢みたいに綺麗で泣けちゃうな
This is beautiful like a dream, and makes me want to cry.
これからたくさんイイコトあるよ
From now on, many good things await us.
もし手を伸ばしたら届くかな
Maybe if I stretch my hand, I can reach it.
明るい空
In this bright sky,
見つけた一筋の流れ星
I found a single shooting star.
柔らかな香りの部屋が好き
I love this room with a mild fragrance,
楽しい思い出を数えるのが好き
and I like to count all of the funny memories.
悩みとか迷いもあるけれど
There are times when we feel insecure and lost, but
覗く角度変えたらいつでも元気になるよ
if we just change our viewpoint, we can always get better.
ほら
Look,
寂しくないからね
it isn't lonely at all,
まぶしい光のモニュメント
because we have this brightly shining monument.
夢みたいに綺麗で泣けちゃうね
This is beautiful like a dream, and makes me want to cry.
これから何度もイイコトあるよ
From here on there will be heaps of good things.
伸びる影法師見送る風
A breeze blows into my outstretched silhouette.
明るい空 見上げてまた一筋の流れ星
In this bright sky, I found yet another shooting star.
例えば魔法が使えたね
If we could use some magic,
フェルトの羽を背中に貼り付けて
I'd stick felt feathers on our backs
雲の間隙から飛び立つよ
so that we could fly between the rifts in the clouds.
夢みたいに綺麗で泣けちゃうよ
This is beautiful like a dream, and makes me want to cry.
明日も明後日もその次も
Tomorrow, the day after, and even the days after it,
素敵なデキゴトの花束を
holding a bouquet made of wonderful events
両手に抱えて駆け出す
in each hand, let's run
夕暮れの街角
towards the corner of the sunset.
もし手を伸ばしたら届くかな
Maybe if I stretch my hand, I can reach it.
空に撒いてこぼれたシアワセの花びら
The happiness petals that fell down from the sky
夢吹雪
are colored with our dreams.
夢みたいに綺麗で泣けちゃうよ
This is beautiful like a dream, and makes me want to cry.
明日も明後日もその次の日も
Tomorrow, the day after, and even the days after it,
素敵なデキゴトの瞬きを両手に抱えて
holding the twinkling wonderful events in both hands,
病気にならないで かけがえす夕暮れの街角
don't get sick, at the irreplaceable sunset street corner.
もし手を伸ばしたら届くかな
Maybe if I stretch my hand, I can reach it.
空にまいてこぼれた幸せの花びら
The happiness petals scattered from the sky
夢吹雪
are colored with our dreams.
「はばたきのさ すぐに」 誰かがささやいた
"Let's fly away, right away," someone whispered.
「ひざ下の境界線 飛んでしまおうよ」
"Let's fly away from the boundaries at our feet!"
背中合わせの自由
Back-to-back freedom.
「さびた鎖にとりからながれてなんてなかったんだよ」
"We haven't been bound in these rusty chains from the start."
胸に 胸を詰めて 青色の深目に沈みたい
Packing the sky in my heart, I want to sink deeply into its blue.
どこまでも 果てなく 夜空をまとい 新しい世界を探そう
Clad in the endless night sky wherever we go, let's search for a new world.
会いたくて 会えなくて 揺れまどうけれど 目覚めた翼は消せない
I want to meet you, but I can't meet you, but these wings can't be taken away.
はばたきのさ すぐに
Let's fly away, right away,
誰かがささやいた
someone whispered.
ひざ下の境界線 飛び出そうよ
Let's fly beyond the boundary at our feet!
背中合わせの自由
Back-to-back freedom.
さびた鎖に 最初からつながれてなかったんだよ
We weren't bound to rusty chains from the start, you know.
胸に 胸に 空を 詰めて
Packing the sky in my heart, in my heart,
青色の 深く に 沈み たい
I want to sink deep into its blue.
どこまでも 果て なく 夜空 を まとい
Clad in the endless night sky wherever we go,
新しい 世界 を 探 そう
let's search for a new world.
会いたくて 会え なく て 揺れ まどう けれども
I want to meet you, but I can't, so I waver,
目覚め た 翼 は 消せ ない
but these awakened wings won't vanish.
何 が 正しい なんて 答え は ない さ
What is right? There's no answer.
枝分かれ した 道 神のみぞ知る
A path that branches off, only God knows.
止められない スピード 加速 する ほど
Unstoppable speed, accelerating more and more,
鼓動 は 高く 高鳴り 覚め て いく よ
my heartbeat pounds higher and higher.
何もかも が 落ち て いく けど
Everything may be falling apart, but
君 だけ は 大人 に なら ない で
just don't grow up into an adult, okay?
懐かしい 光 に 導か れ て
Led by a nostalgic light,
あなた は 優しく 手 を 振る
you gently wave your hand.
見なれた 未来 に も 別れ を 告げ て
Saying farewell to a familiar future,
壊れ た 幻想 を えがこう
let's paint a broken illusion.
定められた 運命 を 切り裂い て 空 へ と 抜け出そう
Let's tear apart this destiny and slip away to the sky!
今 も 今 も 覚め て いる
Even now, even now I remember
幼い 頃 に 見 た 朝焼 を
the warm glow of the morning from my childhood.
どこまでも 果て なく 夜空 を まとい
Clad in the endless night sky wherever we go,
新しい 世界 を 探 そう
let's search for a new world.
会いたくて 会え なく て 揺れ まどう けれども
I want to meet you, but I can't, so I waver,
目覚め た 翼 は 消せ ない
but these awakened wings won't vanish.
懐かしい 光 に 導か れ て
Led by a nostalgic light,
あなた は 優しく 手 を 振る
you gently wave your hand.
見なれた 未来 に も 別れ を 告げ て
Saying farewell to a familiar future,
壊れ た 幻想 を えがこう
let's paint a broken illusion.
定められた 運命 を 切り裂い て 空 へ と 抜け出そう
Let's tear apart this destiny and slip away to the sky!
サラミ ね みたり し たい 潜っ たら ユートピア
Let's dive in and find our utopia!
波 に とけ って じゃあ ぐらい の スピード で もっ て
Riding the waves at lightning speed!
さあ ベキ ベキ だ うん 君 が 壊し て 呼び止め よ
Let's shatter it all and call out!
この 果て ない 宙 ぶら に
In this endless uncertainty,
君 の 手 を 取って 飛び込む よ
taking your hand, I'll dive in!
あぁ もどかしさ の 中 で
Ah, amidst the frustration,
遠ざか って いく
getting further away,
あの 日 の かなしみ よろこび が 全部
all the sadness and joy of that day
君 に なっ て 叫ん だ
became you and shouted out.
さあ 手 を 伸ばし て
Now, reach out your hand!
サラミ ね みたり し たい 潜っ たら ユートピア
Let's dive in and find our utopia!
波 に とけ って じゃあ ぐらい の スピード で もっ て
Riding the waves at lightning speed!
さあ ベキ ベキ だ うん 君 が 壊し て 呼び止め よ
Let's shatter it all and call out!
この 果て ない 宙 ぶら に
In this endless uncertainty,
君 の 手 を 取って 飛び込む よ
taking your hand, I'll dive in!
宇宙 を 舞う 天使 みたい に
Like an angel dancing through space,
like an angel dancing through space,
宇宙 を 舞う 天使 みたい に
like an angel dancing through space.
キライ キライ キライ 言ったって 本心 じゃ ない
Hate, hate, hate, even if I say that, it's not true!
小悪魔 な テクニック
A little devilish technique.
クライ クライ クライ 泣いたって 心配 は ない
Cry, cry, cry, even if I cry, no worries!
涙 さえ 武器 に なる
Even tears become a weapon.
ドキドキ の スパイラル
Doki Doki spiral.
ドキドキラビリンス
[Title: Doki Doki Labyrinth]
誰かを想いながら 夜を眠るの
Who am I thinking of as I sleep at night?
君の夢にお邪魔した
I want to intrude into your dreams.
たまに視線感じはするけど
I sometimes feel your gaze, though,
ちゃんと私だけ見ててよ
so make sure you only look at me!
そばにいたい
I want to be by your side,
この気持ちは変わらない
this feeling won't change.
君の笑顔 君の優しさ
Your smile, your kindness—
見せつけて
show them off to me!
キタイ キタイ キタイ ばっかで 進展がない
Expectations only, no progress!
キライ キライ キライ 言ったって本心じゃない
I say I hate you, but that's not how I really feel
小悪魔なテクニック
A little devil's technique
クライ クライ クライ 泣いたって心配はない
Cry, cry, cry, even if you cry there's nothing to worry about
涙さえ武器になる
Even tears become a weapon
ドキドキのスパイラル
A heart-pounding spiral
誰を想いながら夜を眠るの？
Who are you thinking of as you sleep at night?
君の夢にお邪魔したい
I want to intrude on your dreams
たまに視線感じはするけれど
I sometimes feel your gaze on me
ちゃんと私だけ見ててよ
Make sure you're only looking at me
胸が痛い そばにいたい
My chest hurts, I want to be by your side
この気持ちは変わらない
This feeling will never change
君の笑顔 君の優しさ
Your smile, your kindness
見せつけて
Show them all to me
タイタイタイ ばっかで進捗がない
Tie, tie, tie, it's all ties and no progress
モヤモヤが溜まってく
The haziness keeps piling up
トライトライライ いつだって挑戦者
Try, try, try, I'm always a challenger
結末はわからない
The ending is uncertain
ドキドキのラビリンス
A heart-pounding labyrinth
キライ キライ キライ 言ったって本心じゃない
I say I hate you, but that's not how I really feel
小悪魔なテクニック
A little devil's technique
クライ クライ クライ 泣いたって心配はない
Cry, cry, cry, even if you cry there's nothing to worry about
涙さえ武器になる
Even tears become a weapon
ドキドキのスパイラル
A heart-pounding spiral
他の子たちと喋ってるところを見せたら嫉妬しちゃうかな
Would you get jealous if I talked with other girls?
早くしないと逃しちゃうかもよ
If you don't hurry, you might miss your chance
ボヤボヤしないでお願い
Please don't dawdle
嘘ついたり 距離置いたり
Lying or keeping your distance
臆病風は止まない
Cold feet never stop
恋の仕方 取り扱いは気をつけて
Be careful how you handle love
キライ キライ キライ 言ったって本心じゃない
I say I hate you, but that's not how I really feel
小悪魔なテクニック
A little devil's technique
クライ クライ クライ 泣いたって心配はない
Cry, cry, cry, even if you cry there's nothing to worry about
涙さえ武器になる
Even tears become a weapon
ドキドキのスパイラル
A heart-pounding spiral
good days 恋はスパイラル
Good days, love is a spiral
bad days たまに空回り
Bad days, sometimes spinning our wheels
たりない たりない 努力の日々
Not enough, not enough days of hard work
めげない めげない つまらなくても
Don't give up, even if it's boring
ドキドキのモベピはいつでも君だから
My heart-pounding motivation is always you
誰を想いながら夜を眠るの？
Who are you thinking of as you sleep at night?
君の夢にお邪魔したい
I want to intrude on your dreams
コワイ コワイ コワイ 本当は無理して
Scary, scary, scary, actually pushing myself
強気な子 演じてる
Playing the tough girl
ツライ ツライ ツライ ばかり言いたくない
I don't want to keep saying it's tough
プライドでサバイバル
Surviving on pride
タイタイタイ ばっかで進捗がない
Tie, tie, tie, it's all ties and no progress
モヤモヤが溜まってく
The haziness keeps piling up
トライトライライ いつだって挑戦者
Try, try, try, I'm always a challenger
結末はわからない
The ending is uncertain
ドキドキのラビリンス
A heart-pounding labyrinth
貴方羅組集合ー！
Takaragumi, assemble!
お疲れ様でした！
Good job, everyone!
ライブですね！
It's a live!
我が輩が、お前らの先頭に2周年になった！
Yours truly reached her 2nd anniversary leading you all!
ごっそざす！
Thanks for the feast!
ということで我が輩が一番最初にライブやった！一番先輩なんですけど！
That's why yours truly performed first! Even though I'm the top senior!
で、次はおるいさんのライブが明日あります！
And next, Polka-san's live is tomorrow!
おかかむるいのライブで、みんな楽しみにしててください！
Look forward to Okakamurui's live everyone!
見に来てくれるかな？
Will you come see it?
はーい、こよです。明後日です！
Hi, it's Koyori. The day after tomorrow!
ライブだよ！見に来てくれるかな？
It's a live! Will you come see it?
はーい、さかたです。さかたまもやりますんで、よろしくお願いします。
Hi, it's Sakamata. Sakatama's doing it too, so please look forward to it.
見に来てくれるかなー！
Will you come see it?!
はい、最後はござれ！ござれです！
Yes, and last is Iroha! It's Iroha!
みんな見に来てくれるでござるか？いいござるか？
Will you all come see it? Is that alright?
そして全員の1周年ライブがばーって終わったら？
And once everyone's anniversary lives are all wrapped up...
ホロックス2周年ライブもやります！イエーイ！
We'll also hold a HoloX 2nd anniversary live! Yay!
今年は参加できますからね！
We can participate this year, after all!
ということで、この曲どうだった？我が輩アイドルだった？
So, how was this song? Was yours truly an idol?
アイドルだったよー！
You were an idol!
ラプラスってね、ギャップ作って、ウインクめっちゃよかったよ。
Laplus, that gap you made—your wink was amazing.
ねー。なんのミニさん？ありがとう。
Right? What mini-san? Thank you.
普段さ、のギャップがね、よかった。
The gap from your usual self was nice.
ラプラスダークネスさんだった？
Was that Laplus Darkness-san?
いやいや、可愛いからね。
No, no, because she's cute.
なんかよかったよ、ラプラスアイドルネスちゃん。
Somehow it was great, Laplus Idolness-chan.
あ、うん。アイドル、私服配信のところちゃん呼びしていいのは、あの、小夜利だけなんだよね。
Only Sayori is allowed to call me "chan" during streams.
やめろやめろ。カメラはあの、ラッちゃんて呼ばないでくれ。
Stop it, stop it. Camera, don't call me "Lap-chan".
やめろ、こういうのは、こういう黒はだめです。
Stop, stop. This kind of black is no good.
で、ぼー？
And, bow?
なんか、可愛い。
Somehow cute.
足りない要素がある気がするんだよな。
I feel like something's missing.
え、そう？
Eh, really?
メデちゃんもいいじゃない。
Mede-chan is good too.
ちょっとね、めんどくさくなってきたよね。
You know, it's getting troublesome.
いや、いいよいいよ、このままで。
No, it's fine as it is.
足りないものがあるはずなんだ！
There must be something missing!
身長とかじゃね？
Height or something?
おい、黙れ！
Hey, shut up!
アイドルとしてってこと？
As an idol?
そうだよ。
That's right.
じゃあ、アイドルについて詳しそうな人のところに行ってみる？
Then, shall we see someone who knows idols well?
あ、行く行く！
Ah, let's go!
アイドル行こう！行こう！行こう！行こう！
Let's go to idols! Let's go! Let's go! Let's go!
はい、せーの、ばいばい！
Ready, set, bye-bye!
なんか連れてこられたけど、これは…
I was brought here, but this is...
このライブのアイドル、生徒担当と言えば！
Speaking of the idols and student leaders of this live!
と言えば…
Speaking of...
本気で言ってんの？ねえ、みんな！
Are you serious? Hey, everyone!
この人、とか、
This person, or...
とか普通に言うのに、ラプちゃんでって言わないの？とか言わねえよ！
You say things normally, but why won't you say "Lap-chan"?
言ってるね。これは言ったな。
You are saying it. You definitely said it.
はめられた！
I got set up!
自分から言ってたけどな。言ってたね。
You said it yourself, though. She did.
ライブのときとか、衣装と言うときに、じゃあって決めるアイドルって、かっこよくない？まあ、尊敬はしてるけどね。
Isn't an idol who decides things like costumes with a "Ta-da!" cool?
えー！ラプラス、スバルとのこと尊敬してんの？
Eh! Laplus, do you respect Subaru?
喋るとき、詰まるか？
When speaking, do you choke up?
おい！ぶっすんぞ、お前！尊敬してねえだろ、こいつ！
Hey! I'll punch you! You don't respect her at all!
まつりさん、キュート？
Matsuri-san, cute?
え？まつりキュート？
Eh? Matsuri cute?
わためさん、クール！わための歌、かっこいいでしょ！
Watame-san, cool! Watame's song is so cool, right?
スバルさん、パッション！パッションってなんだ？
Subaru-san, passion! What even is passion?
スバル先輩のパフォーマンスは見ていて元気をもらえますよね。うんうん。
Subaru-senpai's performances always give us energy. Yeah, yeah.
これだ！
This is it!
この3つの要素が揃えば、我が輩は完璧で究極のアイドル！
With these three elements combined, I am the ultimate idol!
ラッちゃんに今足りない要素って何かなあ。
I wonder what element Lap-chan is missing right now.
キッズだからクールさはないよな。キュートって感じでもないよね。
Being a kid, you don't have coolness. You don't feel very cute either.
オーラはパッションというか、ドス黒い感じ。おい全部足りねえじゃねえか！ふざけんなよ！
Your aura is less passion and more pitch-black. Hey, you're missing everything!
こうなったら、出せよ！ゲットボタン！
If it comes to this, bring it out! The Get Button!
そこから、何でもありだ。このボタンでセットを呼び出し、足りない要素を補ってやるぞ！
From there, anything goes. With this button, I'll summon the set!
誰を呼ぶつもりなのかな？それは押してからの お楽しみだよね！
Who do you plan to call? That's the fun part after pressing it!
えいっ！
Take this!
劣等上等 BRING IT ON
Bottom to top BRING IT ON
列島上々 不眠日本
Jumpin' Japan number one
子供騙しのマセマティカ
I'm over all this stupid Mathematica
バレてんだってそんなのってプライドがないや
I don't care 'bout a thing now, no pride left
ご立派 警鐘 気取りで
Putting on a show but I'm over it now
高みの見物ばかりじゃつまんないでしょ
Riding upon a horse up high, I wanna get down
ほらもっと 間違って上等
Again they don't see, that I'm really not king
退屈に手をかけて
And every day repeating all the same
ママ、やっぱあたしは こんなところじゃ終われない
Mama, I dunno what to do, I couldn't stop it tonight
ぬるくて 気 が触れそう
And maybe I'm going crazy
ごっこ遊びも芝居もさようなら
In a fantasy of make believe, I'm living my life
ずっとこのままなんてさあ いらないよ
No more playing around, say goodbye, I don't need it
ダッダッダ あたし大人になる
Da da da I'm growing up and out into the world
酸いも甘いも噛み分けて今
Tasting all of the sweet, maybe even sour things
パッパッパ 変わる時代
Pa pa pa I'm changing up, believe
悪いことばかりじゃないでしょう
In every word that I say cuz it's coming from me
過去も、罪も、罰も、すべて
All the past, all the sin, all the pain I was in
素手で、愛で、生き抜いてやり返すわ
Make it through with my hands, surviving all that I can
挑発 あたし達はno doubt
Yeah, we out, making you crazy no doubt
緑のアイツにばっか構ってんね
Don't be talkin' 'bout that green ho with no flow again
さあburn up いつになったら貰える合格
Yeah, so burn up as I pass in the rearview
赤ペン入れでよ どこがダメなんですか
Need a pen? Any red? Bet I get a hundred and ten
酒女金ドラッグ やっちゃってコンプラ
Girls, liquor, money, and drugs, you know they gonna say yes
チルってaiight... 冗談じゃんブラックジョーク
Chill out, it's aight... Just makin' mean jokes
中指立てたくなるような事情 ありすぎて指足りねえからhands up and what's up
If I gotta raise a middle finger up again, hands up and what's up
劣等上等 bring it on
Bring it on, inferior supreme,
列島上々 不眠日本
archipelago rising, sleepless Japan!
子供騙しのマスメティカ
Childish, deceptive mathematics—
バレてんだってそんなのって
everyone knows it's all a sham,
プライドがないや
leaving us with no pride.
ご立派 警鐘 気取りでさ
Acting like grand alarmists,
高みの見物ばかりじゃつまんないでしょ
just watching from the sidelines gets so boring, right?
ほらもっと 間違って上等
Look, it's fine to make even more mistakes!
退屈に手をかけて
Take hold of the boredom,
ママ、やっぱりあたしはこんなところじゃ終われない
Mama, I know I can't end up stuck in a place like this!
ぬくぬく 気が気じゃない触れそう
Cozy and soothing, almost touching it—
ごっこ遊びも 芝居もさよなら
goodbye to make-believe and acting.
ずっと このままなんてさあ いられないよ
We won't stay like this forever!
ダッダッダ あたし大人になる
Dadadada, I'm growing up into an adult!
酸いも甘いも噛み分けて 今
Savoring both the sour and sweet right now,
パッパッパ 変わる時代
papappa - the times are changing fast!
悪いことばかりじゃないでしょう
It can't be all bad things, can it?
過去も、罪も、罰も、すべて
Past, sins, and punishments—all of them
素手で、愛で、生き抜いてやり直すわ
barehanded, with love, surviving to start over again!
ダッダッダ くだらない
Dadadada, it's so worthless,
言葉がかすれない
words won't fade away.
わかるか？あたしの美学
Do you understand my aesthetic?
この馬鹿正直な拳ひとつが絆なんです
This hopelessly honest fist of mine is our bond!
切り札案外悪くなんてない
A trump card isn't actually bad at all.
がなる劣等 一抜けろさらば！
Roar, inferior ones, and slip away, farewell!
こんなもんじゃない
This isn't all there is to it!
出し惜しみも甘いもかみ分けていま
Savoring both reluctance and sweetness right now,
散々増し歩みライバルはこのままでいいの？
walking on and on, is this rivalry really okay?
痛い！効かない！曲げない！でいぬ抜けちょうどだわ
Painful! Useless! Unyielding! Slipping through is just right!
来てくれて、来てくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming!
自己紹介をお願いします！
Please introduce yourselves!
せーの！ひなたです！雪花です！
One, two! I'm Hinata! I'm Yukihana!
鈴木ひなたです！
And I'm Suzuki Hinata!
いやー、嬉しいね！呼んでくれて嬉しいよ！
Man, I'm so happy! We're so glad you invited us!
まさかこんなところまで来ていただけて...
To think you'd come all the way here...
いや、もう嬉しすぎて、今日こちらまで来ていただいて...
We were so happy, and to come all this way today...
それで、この3人といえば、まず生放送に来てもらって！
And speaking of us three, first you came on our live stream!
そのあとね、コラボで、歌コラボで！
And then after that, we did a singing collaboration!
あ、もう出てるね！はい、マトリョシカ歌いました！
Ah, it's already out! Yes, we sang "Matryoshka"!
まぁ、我々のチャンネルに上がってるね！
It's up on our channel, right?
やっぱ、お二人、めっちゃ歌上手くて！
You two are really amazing singers!
先にお二人が収録した歌を聞きながら...
While listening to the vocals you two recorded first...
私も歌ったんですけど...上手...
I sang mine too... so good...
いや、もうセクシーボイスが素晴らしくて！
Your sexy voices were just incredible!
いやもう、ありがとうございます！嬉しい！
Thank you so much! I'm so happy!
いやもう世界一大好きだよ！世界一大好き！
I love you more than anyone in the world! Absolutely love you!
でもやっぱお二人が一番ね、真ん中ですし...
But you two are right in the middle, and...
間に挟まれるなんてちょっと...
Getting sandwiched between you two like this is a bit...
いや本当に、今回劣等上等歌ったんですけど...
Seriously, we sang "Bring It On" this time...
いや、めっちゃ歌いながら踊るのがやばいっすね！
Dancing while singing is seriously intense!
みんなちょっと疲れ気味で...元気いっぱいね！
Everyone's looking a bit tired... full of energy!
でもやっぱ、お二人のやつがかっこよすぎて！
But your version was just too cool!
この曲覚えたんで！
That's why I learned this song!
いや本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you so much, really!
ほら、みんな！
Hey everyone!
盛り上がっております！
Things are getting hyped up!
コメント欄もうわあってなったよね
The comment section went wild, right?
ねえ、ありがとう！
Yeah, thank you!
やっとですね、はい
Finally, yes.
でも、また？
But again?
ねえ、またコラボしたい、したい！
Hey, I want to collab again!
いや、今回ちょっとかっこいい系の曲を連続で、それをしか、レトルトさんとかでやったんで
Well, this time we did cool songs back to back, like with Retort-san.
ちょっと次は結構楽しいのとかやりたい！
Next time I want to do something fun!
あーいいね！ポップ系？姫ヒナさんかわいいっていうか
Ah, nice! Pop style? HimeHina-san is cute, or rather...
ちょっとキュートっぽい感じの曲を歌ってる印象がやっぱなくて、やっぱクールな、アーティストだから
She doesn't really have the impression of singing cute songs, being a cool artist.
あ、そうそうアーティストだからそう、アーティストだから
That's right, she's an artist, so she's an artist.
そう、普段はちょっとこういう感じなんだけど、歌ってるととめっちゃかっこいいんで
Normally she's like this, but when she sings, she's super cool.
ちょっとねこういう感じ日常っぽい感じの、歌とかよりやりたい！
I want to do everyday-style stuff more than just songs!
やりたい！やりたい！これはもう決まったと！
I want to do it! This is already decided!
すでにね、みんな覚えといてね
Everyone remember that, okay?
あ、現実に捉われました、現実捉えました、こと取り戻しました、こと取り戻し
Caught in reality, but we got things back.
まあ、じゃあクールはもうマスターしたということで、完璧だよ、もう二人のおかげで！
Well, since you've mastered cool, it's perfection, thanks to these two!
マスターしましたよ！やったー！マスターしました！ありがとうございます！
I mastered it! Yay! Thank you very much!
じゃあ次のセッションも代わりますので、何々大丈夫です、大丈夫です！
Well, the next session will change too, what what, it's okay!
じゃあもう頑張って、アイドル目指して頑張ってね！
Well then, do your best, aim to be idols!
ねえみんな、ねっ、アイドル目指せ、ありがとう、バイバーイ、ありがとう！
Hey everyone, aim to be idols, thank you, bye-bye!
バイバーイ！あ、じゃあ一緒に行こう！
Thank you very much, bye-bye, let's go together!
今なんじゃない?
Isn't this the moment?
メラメラとたぎれ
Blazing and surging,
眠っているだけの正義
a justice that was just sleeping.
こんな僕も君のヒーローになりたいのさ
Even someone like me wants to be your hero.
かっこいい君には僕じゃ頼りないのかななんて
For someone as cool as you, maybe I'm not enough to rely on?
そりゃそうだなだって今もこうして迷ってる
That's right, because even now I'm still lost like this.
手を取ってくれないか
Won't you take my hand?
ギブとテイクさ
It's give and take,
君が僕のヒーローだったように
just like you were my hero.
今なんじゃない?
Isn't this the moment?
メラメラとたぎれ
Blazing and surging,
こんな僕にも潜る正義が
a justice hidden even within someone like me.
どうしようもない衝動に駆られて
Driven by an unstoppable urge,
ほら気付けば手を握っている
look, before I knew it, I was holding your hand.
いったいぜんたいそんなに荷物を背負い込んでどこへ行くの
Just where are you going, carrying such a heavy load?
ねえねえ待って僕にちょっと預けてみては?
Hey, wait, why not leave a little with me?
信じてばかりの僕と
Me, who only knows how to believe,
信じることが怖い君と
and you, who are afraid to believe—
どちらが正しいのかななんて
which of us is right?
誰にも分からないさ
Nobody knows.
僕らだけの世界
Our very own world.
ギブとテイクさ
It's give and take.
補い合った暁には同じ夢を見たい
In the dawn we share, I want to dream the same dream.
君はかっこいいと苦しめたりひとりぼっちにさせたのは少し僕のせいなんだよねごめんね
If making you suffer or leaving you alone was partly my fault, I'm sorry.
だけど見るべきはリアルだ今こそ僕が救えるんだ
But reality is what we must see; now is when I can save you.
抱えないで信じて頼ってほしいんだ
Don't shoulder it all; I want you to believe in and rely on me.
今なんじゃない? メラメラとたぎれ
Isn't this the moment? Blazing and surging,
ほっとけない
I can't just leave you be.
そんなに荷物を背負い込んでどこへ行くの
Just where are you going, carrying such a heavy load?
ほんのちょっと僕にちょっと預けてみては?
Won't you leave just a little bit of it with me?
こんな僕も君のヒーローになりたいのさ
Even someone like me wants to be your hero!
LALALA
聞いてくれてありがとう！
Thank you for listening!
キミたちありがとうー！
Thank you guys so much!
いやー、ちょっとチルから、自己紹介お願いします。
Man, let's chill and do self-introductions.
はい！雪花ラミィです、よろしくお願いします！
Yes! I'm Yukihana Lamy, nice to meet you!
はい、紫咲シオンです、よろしくお願いします！
Hi, I'm Murasaki Shion, nice to meet you!
いや、久しぶりですか？
Man, has it been a while?
えっ、なんで忘れて…
Eh, why did you forget...
Vさいらいざろ！
V-Sai was last year!
あ、そうでした、そうでした！
Ah, that's right, that's right!
いや懐かしいよ、半年前以上前っていうことで。
Man, it brings back memories, being over half a year ago.
はい、はい。
Yeah, yeah.
いや、久しぶりっすね。
Man, it really has been a while.
久しぶり！久しぶりです！
Long time no see! It's been a while!
いや、あの時は誘ってくれてありがとうございました。
Yeah, thank you so much for inviting me back then.
いや本当にみんなでね、できてよかったよね。
Yeah, I'm really glad we all got to do it together.
いや、お世話になりました、ありがとうございました。
Thank you for taking care of us, thank you very much.
誘ってくれて嬉しかったよ、誘ってくれて。
I was so happy you invited me.
いや今日はね、お二人をお呼びが誘って集めたんで。
Well, today I invited and gathered these two here.
次は何、何？
Next is me, huh?
ファンのみんなはどんな形でもいいから見たいなという...
I wanted to see everyone's form of EDM.
ちょっと嬉しい、いいことした。
So I'm really glad I did that!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
どうでしたか？
How was it?
めっちゃ難しかった！
It was hard!
すごく練習してくれて...
You practiced so hard for me!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
久しぶりだね！
It's been a while, right?
今回はアイドルを目指していって、どうですか？
We aimed to be idols this time, how is it?
黙んなよ！
Be quiet!
ファッションは完璧だったよね！
Fashion was perfect, right?
アイドルはな、ファッションだけじゃ足りなくて...
Idols need more than just fashion!
可愛いくない？
You're cute, right?
がんばります！
I'll do my best!
ちょっと頑張ります！エルください、エル！
I'll do my best! Give me an L!
次のキュートも頑張ってね！
Do your best for the next cute thing too!
またね、ばいばーい！
See you later, bye-bye!
もうしゃーないじゃあ、ありがと、ばいばーい！
That's all, then bye-bye!
そのとき空から不思議な光が降りてきたのです…
At that moment, a mysterious light descended from the sky...
(あ、あれはだれだぁ！だれだぁ！だれなんだぁ！)
(Ah, who is that?! Who is that?! Who could that be?!)
それは… …ななでーす
That is... Nana-desu!
あ、ちょっとひかないでください！
Ah, please don't pull back!
ウサミンパワーでメルヘンチェンジ
Märchen change with Usamin power!
夢と希望を両耳にひっさげ
Tucking dreams and hopes behind both ears,
なな、がんばっちゃいまいーす
Nana will do her very best!
ミン・ミン・ミン ミン・ミン・ミン ウサミン！
Min-min-min, min-min-min, Usamin!
デンパでOK 受信でOK
Denpa is OK, reception is OK,
ウサミン ウサミン グルコスミン
Usamin, Usamin, Glucosamin!
こころはちゃんと通じてるんです
Our hearts are truly connected,
“きゅうと きゅーち きゅーちくるっくー”
"Cute, cute, cute-churu-ku!"
歌うもOK ダンスもOK
Singing is OK, dancing is OK,
ウサミン ウサミン プロビタミン
Usamin, Usamin, Provitamin!
これでもちゃんとUになるんです
Even so, I properly become a U!
“ハートウェーブ！ピリピリイン！”
"Heart wave! Pili-pili-in!"
ウサミン ウサミン 電車で迎えれば一時間
Usamin, Usamin, an hour away by train,
ウサミン レム睡眠
Usamin, REM sleep.
“あーっ、ここはウサミン星じゃない！？
"Ah, this isn't the Usamin planet?!
のりすぎちゃった～！
I got too carried away~!
だれだ、いちっ、にっ、ななーっ！”
Who is it, one, two, Nanaー!"
ウサミンパワーでメルヘンチェンジ みんな大好き
Märchen change with Usamin power, everyone loves you,
すき すき 大好き うーどっかうーん！
Love, love, love so much, u-dou-ka-un!
ウサミンハートにきゅんきゅん きらめくほんとのおきもち
Heart goes kyun-kyun for Usamin, sparkling true feelings,
“きゃはっ！らぶりーじゅーなさいっ☆”
"Kyaha! Lovely ju-nasai☆"
だいじなだいじなときめきだもの！
Because it's a precious, precious flutter!
“わんつーっ！せーのっ！はいっ！”
"One-two! Ready, set, go!"
ミン・ミン・ミン ミン・ミン・ミン ウサミン！
Min-min-min, min-min-min, Usamin!
ウサ・ウサ・ウサ・ウサミン！
U-sa, u-sa, u-sa, Usamin!
全力OK 笑顔でOK
Full power is OK, smiles are OK,
ウサミン ウサミン ドパ・ドパミン
Usamin, Usamin, Dopa-dopamine!
いつかトップにのぼりつめます
Someday I'll climb to the very top!
好き好き 大好き うどんか！
I love, love, love udon prefecture!
うさ耳ハートに キュンキュンときめくよ
My heart flutters with a bunny-ear heart!
ドキドキの気持ち
This pounding feeling...
卯月 17歳
Uzuki, 17 years old!
大事な大事な ときめきだもん
It's precious, so precious, this fluttering moment!
みみみ みみみ うさみ
Ears, ears, bunny ears!
うさうさ うさうさ うさみ
Bunny, bunny, bunny, bunny ears!
全力OK 笑顔でOK うさみ うさみ ドッパトパみ
Full power OK, smiling OK, bunny ears, bunny ears, super-duper-bunny!
いつかてっぺんに昇り詰めます
Someday I'll climb all the way to the top!
なみ なぶり なぶりみ
Wave, caress, caress-y!
発生OK 演技もOK うさみ うさみ すっこころみ
Pronunciation OK, acting OK, bunny ears, bunny ears, deep exploration!
いつかアニメの主役にあります
Someday I'll star in an anime!
ムービー ピピピ
Movie, beep-beep-beep!
うさみ うさみ 体重増すのは1時間
Bunny ears, bunny ears, gaining weight takes an hour!
うさみ フラフラミー
Bunny ears, dizzy bunny!
でも 永遠の17歳だから まだまだいけますよー！
But since I'm eternally 17, I can still keep going!
い ち ー に ー さ ん な ー ！
One, two, three, four!
うさみ パワーで あまねくメルヘンチェンジ
With bunny power, a universal fairytale change!
みんな大好き
Everyone loves it!
好き好き 大好き うどんか！
I love, love, love udon!
うさ耳ハートに キュンキュンときめくよ
My heart flutters with a bunny-ear heart!
ドキドキの気持ち
This pounding feeling...
乙女の秘密だよ
It's a maiden's secret!
大事な 大事な ときめきだもん
It's precious, so precious, this fluttering moment!
もしも私が ななの本当の姿を知っても 好きでいてくれますか？
If you knew my true form as Nana, would you still love me?
なんて！
Just kidding!
キュンキュン キュンキュン このまま行きますよー！
Kyun-kyun, kyun-kyun, we'll keep going like this!
キュンキュン キュンキュン もういっかい！ もういっかい！
Kyun-kyun, kyun-kyun, one more time! One more time!
うさみ パワーで あまねくメルヘンチェンジ
With bunny power, a universal fairytale change!
みんな大好き
Everyone loves it!
好き好き 大好き うどんか！
I love, love, love udon!
うさ耳ハートに キュンキュンときめくよ
My heart flutters with a bunny-ear heart!
ドキドキの気持ち 乙女の秘密だよ
This pounding feeling is a maiden's secret!
大事な 大事な ときめきだもん
It's precious, so precious, this fluttering moment!
1 2 3 4
One, two, three, four!
みみみ みみみ うさみ
Ears, ears, bunny ears!
はあ… はあ… ちょっと…
Haah... Haah... Um...
皆さん、我がいの… メルヘンデビューどうでしたか？
Everyone, how was my... "Märchen Debut"?
今回は、このメルヘンデビューのためにですね、17キログラムのおもりをつけて踊りました！嘘です。
This time, for "Märchen Debut," I danced with a 17-kilogram weight attached! Just kidding.
いつもよりちょっと重めの風邪を…えっと、つけて踊ってみました。
I tried dancing while carrying a slightly heavier cold than usual... um, attached.
すごい思ったよりすごい疲れちゃって、ちょっと上手に歌えなかったんですけど、ダンスもちょっとあれなんですけど、どうでしたか？頑張りました。
It was way more tiring than I expected, and I couldn't sing very well, and my dancing was also a bit... well, how was it? I did my best.
そして、え、何やら、え、メルヘンデビューを、ここの周年ライブで、え、披露したということで、なんか、バンダイナムコさんから、動画が届いているみたいです。
And um, apparently, since I performed "Märchen Debut" here at my anniversary live, it seems a video has arrived from Bandai Namco-san!
クレームだったらどうしよう。ちょっと怖いんですけど…
What if it's a complaint? I'm kind of scared, but...
ちょっと見ていきましょう。おね… お願いします。
Let's take a look. Please... please.
はい、ええ、ラプラス・ダークネス様、活動2周年おめでとうございます！
Yes, um, Laplus Darknesss-sama, congratulations on your 2nd anniversary of activities!
うめきさんじゃ無い？ ちょ、あのイベントのね… あ、ええ、バンダイナムコエンターテインメントの、アイドルマスター ライブイベントのプロデューサーをしております、うめきと申します。
Umeki-san, right? Wait, for that event... Ah, um, I am Umeki, serving as the producer for Bandai Namco Entertainment's Idolmaster live events.
そしてですね、活動2周年ということで、この先5年、10年と末永く活動していただき、輝きの向こう側を目指していただければと思っております。
And as it's your 2nd anniversary, I hope you will continue your activities for 5, 10, and many more years to come, aiming for "the other side of brilliance."
よろしくお願いします。応援してます。
Best regards. I'm rooting for you.
はい、え、そしてですね、アイドルマスターシリーズの方も負けないように頑張っていきたいと思っております。で、アイドルマスターシリーズですけれども、きたる12月9日、10日にですね、東京ドームでラブライブ…
Yes, um, and also, we hope to work hard so the Idolmaster series won't be outdone. And regarding the Idolmaster series, on upcoming December 9th and 10th at Tokyo Dome, Love Live...
お笑いさんと一緒にうた合戦を開催いたします。
We'll be holding a song battle alongside comedians.
はい、えー、この、えーイジゲンフェスアイドルマスターラブライブ！うた合戦ですね、
Yes, regarding this "Isekai Fest Idol Master Love Live! Song Battle,"
えー、ラプ様が、えーアンバサダーとして就任いただくことが決定しております。
it has been decided that Lap-sama will serve as the ambassador.
そうなんですー。
That's right!
え、ぜひですね、えー、担当アイドル、担当アイドル以外のアイドルもですね、ラプ様に、えー、プロデュースしていただき、うた合戦を盛り上げていただければと思います。よろしくお願いいたします。
I hope you'll produce idols—both your own assigned ones and others—and make the song battle a success. Thank you very much.
はい、それでは活動2周年、え、おめでとうございました。
Yes, and congratulations on your 2nd anniversary!
これからも引き続きアイドルマスター、よろしくお願いいたします。
Please continue to support Idol Master from now on as well.
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
うーちゃん！元気おじさん！アイマス大好き元気おじさん！
U-chan! An energetic old man who loves Idol Master!
わあ、ありがとうございます！なんとアイマスシリーズのライブの企画運営を統括していらっしゃるうーちゃんさんからメッセージをいただきました！ありがとうございます！
Wow, thank you so much! I actually received a message from U-chan, who oversees planning and management for Idol Master series lives! Thank you!
そうです、なんと私今回ですね、「ラブライブ！」と「アイマス」の合同ライブ、「異次元フェス」のアンバサダーに就任しました！ありがと、イェーイ！
That's right, and guess what? I've been appointed as the ambassador for the joint "Love Live!" and "Idol Master" concert, "Isekai Fest"! Yay!
ということでね、いやもう、大好きなアイマスに、ちょっとでも携わるお仕事ができっていうのがすごい嬉しくてですね、いやあみんな、イジゲンフェス注目してください！
So yeah, I'm just so happy to be able to work even a little bit with Idol Master, which I love so much. Everyone, please look forward to Isekai Fest!
いやめっちゃ可愛かったでしょ！我が！
Man, wasn't she super cute? Yours truly!
キュートも完璧だ！ありがとー！次！
Cute and perfect! Thank you! Next!
よし！これで全てのピースは揃った！
Alright! Now all the pieces are gathered!
これで我が輩はまさに完璧で究極！
With this, yours truly is truly perfect and ultimate!
触り足りないだけだろ。
You just want to touch it, don't you?
心なしか薄汚れたオーラが変化してきている気がするよ。
I feel like your tainted aura is somehow changing.
なんか、どんどん言い方ひどくなってない？
Hey, aren't you getting more and more harsh?
正直、どこらへんがかわったかわからないでござるなあ。
Honestly, I can't really tell what changed.
そんなチクチク言葉を投げかけては、
Throwing such sharp words around like that...
ラプちゃんが燃え尽きてるー！
Lap-chan is burning out!
ラプちゃん？
Lap-chan?
うわ、そらさん。
Oh, Sora-san.
ラプちゃんにとって「アイドル」って何？
What does "idol" mean to Lap-chan?
それは…
That is...
そらさんみたいなの！完璧で可愛くてかっこよくて元気がもらえる最強で無敵のアイドルです！あと、
Someone like Sora-san! The strongest, invincible idol who is perfect, cute, cool, and gives you energy! And also...
とか言わない！
Don't say things like that!
そら先輩の前でとか言うな！
Don't say things like that in front of Sora-senpai!
ラプちゃん、アイドルってね、完璧じゃなくてもいいんだよ。
Lap-chan, being an idol doesn't mean you have to be perfect.
何回転んでも笑顔で起き上がって頑張って、たとえ一人でもその人のおかげで生きていける人がいたら、きっとそれが最高のアイドルと思うの。
Even if you fall down many times, get back up smiling and try your best—if there is even one person who can live on because of you, I'm sure that's the greatest idol.
マジで泣きかけた。
I actually almost cried.
ラプ殿はこういうアイドルもののコンテンツにめっぽう弱いでござるからな。
Lap-dono is exceptionally weak to these kinds of idol contents, after all.
だから、ラプちゃんがなりたいものになろう。
So, let's become what Lap-chan wants to be.
アイドルでも、アイドルじゃなくても。
Whether as an idol, or not as an idol.
そらさん、ありがとうございます！あと結婚してください！
Sora-san, thank you very much! Also, please marry me!
とさかさに紛れても無理だろう。
Sneaking that in amidst the nonsense won't work.
いいんだよ、一緒に頑張ろうね！あと結婚は無理かな。
It's okay, let's do our best together! Also, marriage might be impossible.
そりゃそうだろう。
Well, of course.
そらさん、我が輩、何があっても諦めません！世界征服も、アイドル活動も！
Sora-san, no matter what happens, yours truly will never give up! World domination and idol activities alike!
そらさんも！最後のもう諦めろよ。
And Sora-san too! Give up on that last part already.
うん、応援してるよ！あと結婚は無理かな。
Yep, I'm rooting for you! Also, marriage might be impossible.
そりゃそう「でござる」。
Well, of course "it is."
今なら何でもできる気がするもん！我が輩、頑張っちゃうからねー！
Right now, I feel like I can do anything! Because yours truly is going to do her best!
ねえ アイドル に なり たい
Hey, I want to become an idol,
すっごい 愛 を あげ たい
I want to give you amazing love.
この いのち の 使い方 を 君 に 愛さ れ たい
I want to be loved by you for how I use this life.
IDOL SONG 作詞・作曲：大森靖子
[Title: IDOL SONG / Lyrics & Music: Seiko Oomori]
はーい！えくぼは恋の落とし穴
Hii! Dimples are love's pitfall,
夢中にさせちゃうぞ埼玉県から来ました
making you obsessed! I came from Saitama Prefecture,
フレッシュレモンになりたいのー
wanting to become a fresh lemon!
ファンの方が恋人です真面目なアイドル
My fans are my lovers—a serious idol,
真面目にアイドル年中無休24時間ずっと笑顔でうさちゃんピース
seriously an idol, working 24/7 all year round with a constant smile and bunny peace!
はーい！
Hii!
あなたの心にホールインワン
Hole-in-one in your heart,
あなたのハートにアクセスします
accessing your heart,
みんなのドキドキにシュートします
shooting for everyone's heartbeat!
なんでもいいからレスください
Give me a fan service, whatever it is!
ハゲ気味のみなさーん？
Everyone who's a bit balding?
のおおおおおおお！
Nooooooo!
よし、今日もかわいいこゆビーム！
Alright, today is also a cute Koyubi-beam!
ねえ アイドル が たのしい
Hey, being an idol is fun,
いっぱい 愛 が まい て いる
with so much love dancing around.
ステージ から 見る 景色 が ずっと 宝物 さ
The scenery seen from the stage is forever my treasure.
ねえ もし 君 が 他界 し た と し て も 君 が 必要な分の幸せは与えられていたかな
Hey, even if you stopped being a fan, I wonder if I was able to give you all the happiness you needed.
はーい 好き で いい よ はーい もっと 大胆 に はーい 好き で いい よ はーい もっと 叫べ
Hii, it's okay to love me! Hii, be more bold! Hii, it's okay to love me! Hii, shout out louder!
ああっ、お姉さま。
Ah, Onee-sama.
あのぅ、吾輩、三日くらいお風呂入ってないんですけどぅ…
Um, I haven't taken a bath in about three days...
あのオッ、お願いがありましてぇ…
I have a favor to ask you...
吾輩の耳、舐めて欲しいですぅw
I want you to lick my ears, lol.
お姉さま♡ ああっ お姉さま ♡
Onee-sama♡ Ah, Onee-sama♡
すぅ はぁ すぅ はぁ お姉さま ♡
Inhaling, exhaling, Onee-sama♡
お姉さま ♡ ああっ お姉さま ♡
Onee-sama♡ Ah, Onee-sama♡
お ・ ね ・ え ・ さ ・ ま 〜 〜 〜 ！
O-ne-e-sa-ma~~~!
世の中のお姉さまに捧ぐ
Dedicated to all the Onee-samas in the world,
（あ、お姉さま ♡ ああっ お姉さま ♡）
(Ah, Onee-sama♡ Ah, Onee-sama♡)
起きたら耳元で囁いて
Wake me up and whisper in my ear,
（あ、お姉さま ♡ ああっ お姉さま ♡）
(Ah, Onee-sama♡ Ah, Onee-sama♡)
胸元に滴るその汗を
That sweat dripping down your chest...
「吾輩のお紅茶に入れてゴックンしたいっw」
I want to put it in my tea and gulp it down!
ツノ ツノ ツノ 掴んでちょうだい
Grab my horns, my horns, my horns!
ハンドル代わりを ほ ぇ ほ ぇ ほ ぇ
Use them like handlebars, ho-e ho-e ho-e!
あっ♡あっお姉さま、あっ、ごめんなさい！
Ah♡ Ah, Onee-sama, ah, I'm sorry!
こんな歌、歌ってごめんなさい〜っ！
I'm sorry for singing a song like this~!
おっ、お仕置きぃ！そう！お仕置きしてください！
Oh, punishment! Yes! Please punish me!
尻尾から手ぇ突っ込んでぇ、
Shove your hand right up from my tail,
ツノおっ！ツノおガタガタ言わせてください、ガタガタァ！
Make my horns chatter, chatter away!
あっ、お姉さま！本日はガーターベルトですか！？
Ah, Onee-sama! Are you wearing a garter belt today?!
ガタガタだけにw あっ好きですw
Just like the chattering, lol. Ah, I love it, lol.
えっ！？お姉さま！あっ！お姉様来ちゃう！！お姉さま！
Eh?! Onee-sama! Ah! Onee-sama's coming!! Onee-sama!
あああっ！お世話になっておりゃぁぁぁすっ！！！
Aaaaah! Thank you so much for taking care of meeee!!!
ありがた や や ありがたや
How grateful I am, how grateful I am!
泥酔なんですって お姉さま！（お姉さま！）
You're totally wasted, Onee-sama! (Onee-sama!)
雑魚 雑魚 言ってください
Call me small fry, call me small fry!
残さず飲み込むぞ（飲み込むぞ）
I'll swallow it all down without leaving a drop
愛のムチムチ 愛の鞭
Thick love, the whip of love!
お願いなっぶって お姉さま！（お姉さま！）
Please whip me, Onee-sama! (Onee-sama!)
キモくてごめんなさい
Sorry for being gross.
ありのままで キャストオフ
Just as I am, cast off!
お姉さま ♡ ああっ お姉さま ♡
Onee-sama♡ Ah, Onee-sama♡
すぅ はぁ すぅ はぁ お姉さま ♡
Inhaling, exhaling, Onee-sama♡
お姉さま ♡ ああっ お姉さま ♡
Onee-sama♡ Ah, Onee-sama♡
お ・ ね ・ え ・ さ ・ ま 〜 〜 〜 ！
O-ne-e-sa-ma~~~!
刮目せよ！ymdはもう古い！！！時代はysoだ！
Behold! YMD is already old! The era of YSO is here!
ysoとは何か！？そうっっっ！！！
What is YSO?! That's right!!!
【やたらセクシーなお姉さま！】だぁっ！！！
[An unnecessarily sexy Onee-sama!] That's it!
yso！yso！yso！yso！yso！yso！ysooooooooo！
YSO! YSO! YSO! YSO! YSO! YSO! YSOoooooooo!
やたら セクシーなお姉さま！
An unnecessarily sexy Onee-sama!
ほわんか ドジっ子 姐御肌（姐御肌）
Fluffy, clutzy, big sister vibe (big sister vibe)
クーデレ ツンデレ 小悪魔系（小悪魔系）
Kuudere, tsundere, little devil type (little devil type)
いろんな姉が、いるけれど（いるけれど）
There are all sorts of big sisters (all sorts of big sisters)
あらあらウフフ が優勝ですw（優勝ですw）
"Ara ara ufufu" takes the crown, lol
餅肌！（ぷにぷに） 太もも！？（スリスリ）
Mochi skin! (Squishy) Thighs?! (Rubbing)
ぎゅして！（むにむに） 居なけりゃ！？（無理無理ぅぅぅ）
Hold me tight! (Squishy) What if you're not here?! (No way!)
あぁん、お姉さまがいない世界なんて耐えられないでちゅうううう！！
Aah, I can't endure a world without Onee-samaaa!!
そうして、吾輩は、赤ちゃんになった。
And so, I became a baby.
なでなで、よしよしされる幸せな世界。
A happy world of being patted and caressed.
今日もまた、お姉さまの太ももに顔をうずめ、
Today once again, burying my face in Onee-sama's thighs,
涎を垂らす。これが、人生なのだ。
And drooling. This is what life is all about.
キモく 正しく 美しく
Grossly, righteously, beautifully,
おいげにって言って お姉さま（お姉さま！）
Say "oige ni", Onee-sama (Onee-sama!)
抱っこ 抱っこ してください
Hold me, hold me in your arms.
本能剥き出しぞ（剥き出しぞ）
Unleashing pure instinct (unleashing pure instinct)
足のムチムチ 胸のムチィ
Chubby legs, chubby chest.
失礼します お姉さま（お姉さま！）
Excuse me, Onee-sama (Onee-sama!)
全裸でごめんなさい
Sorry for being completely naked.
ありのままで キャストオフ
Just as I am, cast off!
愛しています お姉さま ♡
I love you, Onee-sama ♡
お姉さま ♡ ああっ お姉さま ♡
Onee-sama ♡ Ah, Onee-sama ♡
すぅ はぁ すぅ はぁ お姉さま ♡
Inhaling, exhaling, Onee-sama ♡
お姉さま ♡ ああっ お姉さま ♡
Onee-sama ♡ Ah, Onee-sama ♡
お ・ ね ・ え ・ さ ・ ま 〜 〜 〜 ！
O-ne-e-sa-ma~~~!
ねぇ、愛してるが楽しい
Hey, loving is fun,
いっぱい愛が重なってる
Love is piling up so much,
ステージから見る景色が
The scenery seen from the stage
ずっと宝物なのさ ねぇ！
Is forever my treasure, hey!
はぁ…ちょっと最近寒いなぁ…。
Haa... It's gotten a bit cold lately...
もうラプラスダークネス1周年記念…じゃなくて2周年記念グッズで生活するのも限界だ！
Living solely on Laplus Darkness 2nd anniversary merch has reached its limit!
話は聞かせてもらいましたよ！
I've heard your story!
どれ？ いや、お姉さん。
Which one? No, Onee-san.
ちょうどいいですわ！
This is just right!
よ、何が？
Yo, what is?
最近寒いよね。分かる。
It's cold lately, right? I know.
そんなあなたに！
For someone like you!
えっ！？じゃーん！
Eh?! Ta-da!
ラプラスダークネス2周年記念グッズパーカー！
The Laplus Darkness 2nd Anniversary Commemorative Hoodie!
えぇっ！？タイミングがいい！
Eeeh?! Perfect timing!
そしてなんと！
And what's more!
ステッカーも付いてきます！
Stickers are included too!
なんか…お得感！
It feels like... such a good deal!
でも、お互いセットで1万円いっか。悔い気味！
But both together for 10,000 yen? A bit regretful!
でもパーカーとステッカーセットで買っても、特典とかないとな…。
Still, buying the hoodie and sticker set doesn't come with any special bonuses...
セットで買ってくれた人限定で直筆サイン入りチェキ風ブロマイドカード、特製ボイス付いてくる！
For those who buy the set, it comes with a handwritten signed bromide card and a special voice!
直筆…！？
Handwritten...?
全員！？えっ！ボイスも！？買った！ありがとうございます！
Everyone?! Eh! Voice too?! Bought it! Thank you very much!
じゃあください。今寒くて…。届くのは来年？
Then please give it to me. It's cold now... It arrives next year?
そんなバカなっ！
No way!
記念グッズ2種、パーカー、ステッカー（3種入り）
2 commemorative goods: Hoodie, Stickers (set of 3)